stechguide.com 2019-07-13

# Privacy Policy

### STechGuide.com respects your privacy.

We respect your privacy and we are committed to safeguarding your privacy while online at our site www.stechguide.com. We safeguard your personal information and never sell it with any third parties.

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.stechguide.com and mailing address is: stechguide@gmail.com

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection (Using  _Akismet: Check Akismet  [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/) here_)

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Log Files

Like many other Web sites, STechGuide.com makes use of log files. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol ( IP ) addresses, type of browser, Internet Service Provider ( ISP ), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and the number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

### Cookies

“Cookies” are small pieces of information (text files) that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing the website. These text files that can be used by websites to make a user’s experience more efficient.

The law states that we can store these cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of this site.

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to save your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year. We also use third-party advertising companies (Google Adsense) to serve ads when you visit our Site, and they may deploy cookies in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

For more information on how to set your browser cookie restrictions, please refer to your browsers help function. Please be aware that restricting cookies could seriously restrict the functionality of our website.

### **Analytics**

We use analytics services (Google Analytics) to help analyze how users use the Site. Google Analytics uses Cookies to collect information such as how often users visit the Site and we use the information to improve our Site and Services. The data we collect will be processed anonymously and “Data sharing” is disabled.

Google Analytics’ ability to use and share information collected by them is restricted by their terms of use and privacy policy, which you should refer to for more information about how these entities use this information. In order to be compliant with the new regulation, Google included a [data processing amendment](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/dpa/dataprocessingamendment_20130906.html). You can also visit [Google Analytics’ Help Page](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) to learn how it uses your data and commits to protecting it.

### **Advertising**

Ads appearing on our site are delivered to the Users by our advertising partner –  _Google Adsense_ , who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non-personal identification information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to our website or other websites. Google’s use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to our site and/or other sites on the Internet.

You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). (Alternatively, you can also opt out of a third-party vendor’s use of cookies for personalized advertising by visiting [www.aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).) We are in compliant with GDPR Privacy Policy rules updated by Google and their products [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy).

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

The external sites which are linked to our content or articles are not associated with us. So we are not responsible for external links or sites. So we advise you to read the Privacy Policy of that site before you disclose any of your personal information

## Who we share your data with

We do not sell, trade, or rent Users’ personal identification information to anyone.

STechGuide.com will  **never**  ask for Credit Card details and request that you do not enter it on any of the forms on STechGuide.com.

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

Information collected using Google Analytics is retained for a period of 14 months. After the end of the retention period, the data is deleted automatically.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## How we protect your data

We strictly protect the security of your personal information and honor your choices for its intended use. We carefully protect your data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

  * We keep our software up to date and take a regular audit to improve security.
  * We use the highly strong password everywhere.
  * We are also using security measures provided by CloudFlare to protect the Site. [Check Cloudflare Privacy Policy [Here](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/)]

### Remember The Risks Whenever You Use The Internet

While we do our best to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to STechGuide.com and you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords or other account information. In addition, other Internet sites or services that may be accessible through STechGuide.com have separate data and privacy practices independent of us, and therefore we disclaim any responsibility or liability for their policies or actions.

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us >  **stechguide@gmail.com**
